准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
章鱼身体旅程
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
今天我们要来研究深海轻柔的韵律
Today we study the gentle rhythm of the sea
轻柔的韵律
Gentle rhythm
那没事了
Never mind
海浪
Ocean wave
热带浪
Tropical waves
漩涡
Whirlpool
反向漩涡
Reverse whirlpool
海绵宝宝  把那噪音关了
SpongeBob, turn that noise off
吹一下  他多半就能注意到了
This will get his attention
海绵
Sponge
章鱼哥  你又把自己竖笛给吞了
Squidward, you swallowed your clarinet again
我来取
I'll get it
别
No
不要
Don't
碰
touch
我
me
我得再仔细看看
I'll get a better look
太黑了
It's too dark
所以就要采取极端措施
This calls for extreme measures
取出来了
Got it
末端尖尖的那块不见了
The pointy bit on the end is missing
那个叫做簧
It's called a reed
什么叫做簧
What's a reed
这下可好
Great
我的簧片
My reed
还是
is still
卡在我的
stuck in my
喉咙里
throat
全都要怪你
And it's all your fault
只剩一个办法了
There's only one thing to do
必须去找珊迪
We got to see Sandy
如我所料
Just as I thought
你竖笛末端尖尖的那块
You've got that pointy bit from the end of your clarinet
卡到你喉咙里了
stuck in your throat
你可真是笨手笨脚
That was clumsy of you
才没有
I didn't
都是海绵宝宝他
It was SpongeBob that
也没别的办法了  必须动手术
Well, there's nothing to do for it but surgery
现在正好可以来试试我的新发明
Now is my chance to try out my new invention--
可以用它来解决你的问题
the solution to your problem
一艘潜艇吗
A submarine?
没错  章鱼哥
That's right, Squidward
来给你展示一下
Let me show you
这一整间实验室叫做缩小室
This whole lab is called the Chamber of Shrinkage
到时我会把自己跟潜艇缩到微观尺度
I'll shrink the sub and myself down to microscopic size
接着航行穿越你的大脑
then navigate through your brain
一路开进你的喉咙
down into your throat
从里面取出簧片
and extract the reed from inside
简单
Simple
怎么不干脆缩小簧片
Why don't you just shrink the reed?
章鱼哥啊
Oh, Squidward
老是想着搞费力不讨好的事
always wanting to do it the hard way
都就绪了  章鱼哥
We're all set, Squidward
准备好打镇静剂了没
Are you ready for the sedative?
你确定这样安全吗
Are you sure this is safe?
完全安全
Completely
只要驾驶员很靠谱就行
As long as someone competent is behind the wheel
那是什么
What's that?
祝你做个好梦
Sweet dreams, pardner
忘了给这趟航行打包食物了
I forgot to pack food for the trip
得去我树屋拿点补给品
I've got to get some supplies from my treedome
我不在时  你们负责看守潜艇
and I need you to guard the submarine while I'm gone
你觉得自己办得到吗  海绵宝宝
Do you think you can handle it, SpongeBob?
办得到  珊迪
Can do, Sandy
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
你好  市民
Hello, citizen
你在干什么
What are you doing?
看守珊迪的潜艇
Guarding Sandy's submarine
我从来就没进过潜艇
I've never been in a submarine
进去看看吧
Let's look inside
不行
Can't
我还在看守呢
I'm guarding it
真是的
Oh, man
就不能进去看守吗
Could you guard it from the inside?
还真是
You're right
派大星  你真是个天才
Patrick, you're a genius
开
海绵宝宝和派大星前来报到看守
SpongeBob and Patrick reporting for guard duty
缩小
"Shrink"
精神病医生
我脑子确实一堆毛病
I do have a lot of issues
漂亮
Pretty
我回来了  海绵宝宝
I'm back, SpongeBob
你变得好小
You're so tiny
好大一个海绵宝宝
A giant SpongeBob
派大星
Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
珊迪长得特别大一个了
Sandy's grown to gigantic size
应该不是珊迪长大了  派大星
I don't think Sandy grew, Patrick
而是我们缩小了
I think we shrunk
太傻了
That's silly
你就不觉得更有可能是
Don't you think it's more likely
整个世界都长大了吗
that the entire world grew?
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
那个  潜艇已经安全进入你体内了
Well, the submarine is safely inside you
太棒了
Wonderful
等下
Wait
你在这外面  那谁在开潜艇
If you're out here, then who's in here?
你还是亲眼看一下吧
Well, why don't you take a look for yourself?
海绵宝宝和派大星在我脑袋开小潜艇
SpongeBob and Patrick are piloting
a miniature submarine inside my head
海绵宝宝和派大星
SpongeBob and Patrick
海绵宝宝和
SpongeBob and
最好冷静一点  章鱼哥
You better calm down, Squidward
他们既然都进了你的体内
With them little critters inside you
就千万别老是乱动
I wouldn't be moving around too much
不然会被他们撞到要害的
You can knock them into something important
这是什么地方  派大星
Where are we, Patrick?
不知道  可这里乱糟糟的
I don't know, but it's a real dump
海绵宝宝  派大星
SpongeBob, Patrick
听得到我说话吗
can you hear me?
是珊迪
It's Sandy
她在里面吗
She's in there?
我来救你了  珊迪
I'll save you, Sandy
住手  你们俩小不点白痴
Stop it, you itty-bitty idiot
珊迪  你在哪
Sandy, where are you?
我们这是在哪
Where are we?
你们这是非法闯入  海绵宝宝
You're trespassing, SpongeBob--
闯进了我实验室  我潜艇
in my lab, my submarine--
还闯入了章鱼哥的体内
and you're trespassing inside of Squidward
老觉得这地方样子烂透了
I thought this place was in bad shape
我都听到了
I heard that
还是把你带出去吧  海绵宝宝
Let's get you out of there, SpongeBob
只要找到自动驾驶
All you need to do is locate the autopilot
就能安全带你完成任务
It'll safely take you through your mission
然后从撤离点撤出来
and then out the extraction point
我们弄坏了
We broke it
住手
Stop it
你们要干嘛
What are you trying to do?
害死他吗
Kill him?
这东西比船还难开17倍左右
This is approximately 17 times harder
to drive than a boatmobile
而你从来就没成功开过船
which you're never successfully done
所以千万不要激动
So just take it nice and easy
没问题
No problemo
千万别
Nice and
激动
easy
情况怎么样了
So, how's it going?
我控制不住自己眼球了
I can't control my eyeballs
没事
Don't worry
一会儿就好
It's temporary
现在签下这个
Now, just sign this
豁免声明
好
Okay
这又是什么
Now, what is this?
单纯签个名而已
Just your autograph
留着等你
for when you're, uh
出名
famous
那当然
Of course
我还有大头照呢
I've got headshots, you know
怎么
What the?
章鱼哥
Squidward
怎么回事
What's happening?
快给我
Give me that
快还来
Give it back
不对  给我
No, give it
快还来
Give it back
他们在撞你中枢神经系统
They're hitting your central nervous system
是吗
You think?
你的动作已经失控了
You're not in control of your actions
对不起
I'm sorry
我的动作已经失控了
I'm not in control of my actions
他们偏航了
They've gone off course
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
你失控了
You're out of control
这是什么地方
Where are we?
求救
Mayday
我们在下沉
We're sinking
派大星一直叫个不停
And Patrick won't stop screaming
胃酸水平已经过高了
Those stomach acid levels are way too high
燃料储备就快要用光了
The reserve tanks are almost empty
派大星
Patrick
用完了
Finished
海绵宝宝  一定要逃出去
SpongeBob, you got to get out of there
从胃部直接就能直达食道
It's a straight shot up the stomach to the esophagus
簧片就在那里
where the reed is
只要能找到替代燃料就能完成任务了
You can complete your mission
if we could just access an alternative fuel
就比如天然气
Like natural gas
天然气吗
Natural gas?
就比如这个
Like this
别在我身体里打嗝了
Stop burping inside me
恶心死了
That's disgusting
等一下  章鱼哥
Wait a minute, Squidward
他们可能有办法
They might be on to something
什么
What?
要是你打嗝打得够大
If you could make a big enough burp
就可以通过压载舱过滤二氧化碳
We could filter the CO2 through our ballast tanks
重新发动引擎
refire the engines
乘着冲击波逃出去
and ride the shock wave out of here
他说得对
He's right
什么
What?
就用你的办法了  派大星
We're going through with your plan, Patrick
什么办法
What plan?
打嗝吧  章鱼哥
Now burp, Squidward
已经命悬一线了
Lives are on the line
没想到会是这样的结局
I never thought it would end this way
天然气储备
成功了
It's working
他们朝着食道冲过去了
They're heading for the esophagus
你都吃了什么玩意
What have you been eating?
那俩白痴
Morons
海绵宝宝呼叫珊迪
SpongeBob to Sandy
我们已经抵达异物所在处
We're reached the foreign obstruction
好
Okay
你们得出去想办法移除它
You're going to have to go out and dislodge it somehow
已经在移了
I'm already on it
两小时后
这破锤子什么都砸不碎
This stupid hammer won't break anything
海绵宝宝  做你天生就会的事
SpongeBob, do what you were born to do
跳舞
Dance
还真是  派大星
You're right, Patrick
漩涡转
Whirlpool spin
大家干得漂亮
Good work, guys
任务完成
Mission accomplished
现在你们就只要
Now all you have to do is
滚出我的身体
Get out of my body
滚
Go
长
Grow?
长大
不要啊
No
蟹堡王
就快开门营业了
Almost ready to open
不得退款
好了
There
早安  蟹老板
Good morning, Mr. Krabs
你好  章鱼哥
Hello, Squidward
我的老天啊
Neptune's trousers
你这什么毛病
What's gotten into you?
前来报到  蟹老板
Reporting for duty, Mr. Krabs
章鱼哥  马桶又堵了
Squidward, the toilet's backed up again
那不是女的
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村
就你呢
You there
谁  我吗
Who me?
对  你
Yes, you
速速离开镇子
Get outta town
到美丽的晴空海岸度假区度假
And take a vacation
to beautiful Sunny Seashores Resort
给你吧  先生
Here you go, sir
速速
离开镇子
到美丽的
晴空海岸
度假区
我得速速离开镇子
I got to get out of town
谢了  海绵宝宝
Thanks, SpongeBob
那当然  派大星
Sure, Patrick
我得马上走
I got to get going
都是他叫我的
He told me to
谁啊
Who did?
那个
Well
不太确定  但他有个手提箱
I'm not sure, but he had a briefcase
手提箱
A briefcase
他多半是个雇佣杀手
He might be a paid assassin
可是派大星  你不能走
But, Patrick, you can't go--
不能就这么走
not like this
谁还能跟我一起
Who will go with me
参加下一届水母捕手博览会呢
to the next Jellyfisherman's Expo?
水母捕手博览会
你就只能另外再找朋友了
It will have to be one of your other chums
因为我去意已决
'Cause my mind is set
别决了  求你别决了
Unset it, please unset it
看来我得打包马上就出发了
I guess I'll pack up my stuff and get ready to go
我的
My
衣服
clothes
派大星  那些是我的衣服
Patrick, those are my clothes
我的花生酱
My peanut butter
那是我的花生酱
That's my peanut butter
还有我的腌椰菜
And my pickles
你居然要就这么走了  派大星
I can't believe you're leaving, Patrick
还把我腌椰菜全带走
with all my pickles
我以后再也不会
It's the end of me
待在这了
being here
等等
Wait
留步
Stop
那我们的计划呢
What about all our plans?
早上八点  叫醒派大星
"8:00 a.m., wake up Patrick
早上九点  跟派大星吃海草哥麦片
"9:00 a.m., eat Kelpo with Patrick
早上十点  跟派大星刷牙
"10:00 a.m., brush teeth with Patrick
下午一点  盯派大星
1:00 p.m., stare at Patrick"
还有谁来跟我一起做事啊
Who's going to do all that with me?
对不起  大势不可挡
I'm sorry, there's no stopping the unstoppable
派大星以后永远都不会再
Patrick Star will live no more, forever
住在裤头村了
in Bikini Bottom
可要是你不是派大星呢
But what if you weren't Patrick Star?
不会吧
Oh, no
我不是派大星吗
I'm not Patrick Star?
是派大星没错  但马上你就不是了
You are Patrick Star, but you won't be for long
可以了  派大星
There you go, Patrick
谁都认不出来是你
No one will know it's you
派大星  没事吧
Patrick, you okay?
你们好
Hey, guys
派大星  墨镜挺酷
Patrick, cool shades
派大星  那套伪装不行
Well, Pat, that disguise didn't work
得再加把劲才行
We're going to have to try harder
海绵宝宝  多谢你相助
Yeah, well, thanks, old SpongeBob, for your help
尽管竭尽了全力
It was a noble effort
可惜都是徒劳
but alas, all in vain
没用的
It's no use
我必须得走
I must leave
再见  石头
Good-bye, rock
再见  珊瑚
Good-bye, coral
再见  海草
Good-bye, seaweed
可惜没能想出来哪件衣服更好看
Too bad we couldn't come up with a better costume
再见  天空
Good-bye, sky
有了
That's it
只要你戴上那个海草  就会是
With that seaweed on your head, you could be
对了
I know
我就会是海草怪物哥
I could be Mr. Seaweed Monster Man
从此就能幸福快乐住在裤头村了
And live happily forever after in Bikini Bottom
派大星  已经有个海草怪物哥了
Patrick, there already is a Mr. Seaweed Monster Man
可恶
Darn
没事的  派大星
It's okay, Patrick
当不了怪物就当不了嘛
So you can't be a monster
不过你头顶那株草
But that vegetation on your head
让我想到可以把你扮成什么了
give me an idea of what you can be
打扮好了
You're all set
出来吧  派大星
Come on out, Patrick
裤头村
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
你好啊  小妹
And hello, lady
伪装成功了  派大星
The disguise is working, Patrick
我是说
I mean
派小妹
Patricia
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你都没跟我说过自己交了女朋友啊
you never told me you had a girlfriend
我不是他女朋友
I'm not his girlfriend
我是派
I'm Pat
小妹
tricia
派小妹  派小妹
Patricia, Patricia
兄弟  你女朋友不丑的
Bro, your girlfriend is not ugly
拉里  她其实不是我女朋友
Actually, Larry, she's not my girlfriend
就只是个
She's just a
没事的  兄弟
It's cool, buddy
不用给我介绍你女朋友
You don't have to explain your girlfriend to me
可她不是我女朋友
But she's not my girlfriend
你何必要站这边找我说话呢
I don't know why you're standing here talking to me
应该要跟你女朋友闲聊才对
when you could be talking to your girlfriend
走吧  派小妹
Come on, Patricia
再见
Bye
恭喜你新交上了个女朋友  兄弟
Congratulations on the new girlfriend, dude
海绵宝宝  现在可不适合周日散步
SpongeBob, this is not the time for a Sunday stroll
应该要去上班
It's time for work
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
蟹堡王两小时后才开门营业
the Krusty Krab doesn't open for another two hours
开门根本就没太早这回事  我的小子
There'll be no such thing as opening too early, me boy
不好意思  小姐
Excuse us, Miss
海绵宝宝  你朋友哪位
SpongeBob, who's your friend?
蟹老板  这位是派小妹
Mr. Krabs, this is Patricia
派小妹
Patricia
简直是最美的芳名
The most beautiful sound I've ever seen
海绵宝宝  蟹堡王那边还缺人手吗
SpongeBob, do we need any more help
down at The Krusty Krab?
不缺
No
缺吗
We do?
好
Great
她马上就能入职
She can start right away
蟹堡王
敢问芳名  我身材姣好的大美人
And who are you, my Rubenesque beauty?
那是派小妹
That's Patricia--
蟹堡王新来的员工
our newest Krusty Krab employee
她可真是美丽动人
Well, she sure is stunning
管好客人的事就行了  章鱼哥先生
Just keep your eyes on the customers, Mr. Squidward
嗨  派小妹
Hi, Patricia
这是我给你画的
I drew this for you
要我说  画得可谓跟你异常相像呢
The likeness is uncanny if I do say so myself
谢了  章鱼哥
Thank you, Squidward
上菜了  派小妹
Order up, Miss Patricia
不好意思  章鱼哥
Excuse me, Squidward
这餐是七号桌的
This order goes to table seven
别忘了你的礼节
And remember your manners
四
Four
雷
nee
给雷
foo-nee
那是七号  派小妹
That's a seven, Patricia
蟹老板  是你点了两份蟹堡套餐吗
Mr. Krabs, you ordered two Krusty Meals?
我点了两份套餐吗
Did I order two meals?
我可真傻
Silly me
我自个可没法一口气吃俩蟹堡套餐
I can't possibly eat two Krusty Meals myself
你多半得帮我吃了
I guess you'll just have to help me finish all this food
好吧
Okay
派小妹  虽然我们仅仅
Patricia, we may have only
相识了一小会儿
known each other for a short time now
但我感觉咱俩已经建立了特殊的联系
but I feel like a special connection has been made
胃口真大啊  不过她女人嘛
Quite an appetite, but she's all woman
派小妹  跟你说
You know, Patricia
我这名嘴章鱼的称号可不是白叫的
they don't call me the sizzle-lipped squid for nothing
你这周六晚上有空吗
So are you free this Saturday night?
没空
No
我那时候要跟海绵宝宝比干瞪眼
That's the night SpongeBob and I
are having a staring contest
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
回去工作  你个占便宜的懒鬼
Get back to work, you goldbricking freeloader
一二一二
Hut two, hut, two
黄堡没蟹就不准回来
And don't come back until all those patties are Krabby
既然只剩咱俩了
Well, now that we're alone
周五晚上要不要来约个会  就到
how would you like to be my date Friday night to a
不行
I can't
我那时候要跟海绵宝宝开潜艇到处飞
SpongeBob and I will be flying submarines that night
我得继续蟹那个堡王了
I have to get back to Krusting the Krab
天啊  他们两个为什么对我那么好
Man, why are those two so nice to me?
他们从来没对派大星这么好
They were never this nice to Patrick
太怪了
It's weird
确定周六晚上没空吗
Are you sure about Saturday night?
紧追不放的家伙
Persistent bunch
周天吃早午餐行不行
How about Sunday brunch?
不用了
No thanks
再次感谢
again
可我都预约了两人桌  就在
But I made reservations for two at
我说不用
I said no
不用
No
不行
No way
不用
No
我到底哪里好了
What is it about me
能让他们两个这么友好
that makes those two so friendly?
肯定跟这身伪装有关系
Must have something to do with this disguise
不能再装下去了
I can't wear this any longer
要是秘密身份暴露
If you reveal your secret identity
就只能离开裤头村了
you'll have to leave Bikini Bottom
对不起  海绵宝宝
I'm sorry, SpongeBob
我再也不能这样生活下去了
I just can't live like this anymore
我已经烦透了假装别人了
I'm tired of pretending to be someone I'm not
可爱的派小妹
The lovely Patricia
回到我们身边了
has returned to us
我宣布个事
I have an announcement to make
我在这上了一整天的班
The entire day that I've worked here
想说
I've wanted to say
想说的是
I've wanted to say that, uh
是
that
我会吃掉你们盘子上面的剩菜
that I will eat any leftovers you leave on your plate
你好
Ahoy
那个女服务生
Waitress
不帮我点餐吗
Aren't you gonna take my order?
我马上来  先生
I'll be right there, sir
怎么了  派大星
What's the matter, Patrick?
就  就是那个带手提箱的
Th-that's the guy with the briefcase
就他要把我赶出镇子
The guy who's trying to run me out of town
是杀手
The assassin
需要什么服务  先生
What can I get you, sir?
话说
Say
我该不会在哪见过你吧
don't I know you from somewhere?
没见过
No
对了
That's it
速速离开镇子
Get outta town
我们被他盯上了
He's on to us
我绝不让你得逞
I won't let you do it
你得先使出可怕技俩对付我
You'll have to do something horrible to me
才能把派大星赶出镇子
before I'll let you throw Patrick out of town
派大星
Patrick?
你忘拿传单了
You forgot your flyer
速速离开镇子
"Get outta town
到美丽的晴空海岸度假区
To beautiful Sunny Shore Resorts"
看啊  他并没有要把你赶出镇子
Look, this guy wasn't trying to run you out of town
只是想低价给你提供奢华假期
He just wanted to sell you
a luxury vacation at a modest price
看来我再也用不着这套伪装了
Well, I guess I don't need this disguise anymore
我觉得自己得去洗澡了
I think I need to take a shower
让我搞清楚
So, let me get this straight
你不是女的吗
You're not a woman?
对
No
那就开除你
Well, then you're fired
有事就来办公室找我
If anybody needs me, I'll be in my office
我大概会在里面待个差不多20年
for, I don't know, the next 20 years or so
兄弟  要不要一起回家
Hey, buddy, what do you say we go home
开始做这单子上面的事呢
and get started on this list?